<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Tropi[CKAPP] Rainforest Mod (Continued)</name>
  <packageId>Mlie.TropickappRainforestMod</packageId>
  <author>Mlie</author>
  <url>https://github.com/emipa606/TropickappRainforestMod</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.0</li>
    <li>1.1</li>
    <li>1.2</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies />
  <loadAfter>
    <li>spoonshortage.ADogSaidAnimalProsthetics</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <description>Update of KapTaiN_KaVerNs mod
https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1110093272

[img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/emipa606/RimWorld-Wrapper/master/Notice.png[/img]

Support-chat:
https://invite.gg/Mlie

Non-steam version:
https://github.com/emipa606/TropickappRainforestMod
	
Removed the need for ModCheck and Harmony by using vanilla-patching.	
Initial loading of a new map may take a while due to the large amount of plants that need to spawn.

--- Original Description ---
The purpose of this mod is to add a significant amount of new animals and plants to the Tropical Rainforest and Tropical Swamp Biome and increase their fauna and flora diversity.

____________________________________

Description
The new tropical biomes are challenging biomes with deadly diseases, strong animals, intense rainstorms and a thick jungle canopy that makes movement and expansion a challenge.

Added Animals :

Jaguar, Panda Bear, Tiger, White Tiger, Tapir, Junglefowl, Peafowl, Okapi

Added Plants :

Ferns, Palm Tree, Mahogany Tree, Strangler Fig, Bromeliad, Wild Rice, Bamboo, Taro, Stump Tree, Banana, Lemongrass, Coconut Palm, DreamVine, Heliconia, Jitter-Weed, Wild Smokeleaf, Wild Psychoid, Wild Cotton, Rafflesia, Hive in a tree

Added Consumables :

Taro Root, Coconuts, Bananas, Jitter Berries (drug), Lemongrass, Dream Root (drug and can be used to craft Neutroamine), Honeycomb

Some tips for surviving the rain forest:

- Clear out plants for pathing. The dense jungle will considerably slow down pawns.
- Wood is abundant, but trees take a long time to chop down. Prioritize time and resources and focus on smaller trees and plants when clearing large areas.
- Foraging is a viable food option. Look out for rice, bananas, coconuts and lemongrass.
- While rare, jitter berries, smokeleaf, psycoid, healroot and cotton can also be foraged.
- The rain forest provides a lot of cover. Clear out areas to hit enemies, or use the cover to your advantage.
- Some animals in the rain forest do a lot of damage and are very fast. Choose fights wisely and try to avoid being ambushed.
- The rain forest rains a lot, so consider this when deciding on power and building options.
- Remove rafflesias from your area as these drastically reduce beauty.
- You can stop plant movement sway in the vanilla options menu.

Compatibility

- A Dog Said ... compatibility patch is now integrated. Be sure to put this mod AFTER A Dog Said...

____________________________________
All animals and plants were designed by Coercion
Pith helmet was designed by Thirite</description>
</ModMetaData>